DANIEL PARK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack web developer with a keen interest in solving difficult problems, and experience in JavaScript, Ruby based programming, and event management. My technical abilities, communication skills, and talent for logistics and planning helps me find creative solutions through code for any company.

4 646.533.3142

☑ dpeace926@gmail.com

■ dpark926.github.io

github.com/dpark926

M medium.com/@dpark

in linkedin.com/in/devdanielpark

PROJECTS

My Momentum [1] A personal dashboard featuring an alarm, weather, pomodoro and stopwatch

- Applied CRUD features with React's virtual-DOM to render and update fetched data from custom built API endpoints.
- External APIs include OpenWeatherMap and Google Maps Geocoding to retrieve weather data and city names
- All clocks and timers are built from scratch with algorithms that updates the state's second using setInterval

MTA eTix git | Inspired by the MTA LIRR train ticketing app February 2008 - June 2009

- Built with React's virtual-DOM to render components with animated features
- Used setInterval and new Date() to render the current time and date by updating the state in every second
- Implemented animations using CSS keyframes and Animate CSS
- Injected React inline styles to generate random rgba colors

Meal Buddy An app that allows users to add recipes to a meal planner and creates shopping lists

- Built using React.js as front-end and Ruby on Rails as back-end
- Built custom Rails APIs to handle fetch requests for a fast single page application experience with no refreshes
- Utilized JWT to create access tokens

Piano Roll [1] | A musical interface that displays audio notes and can play midi tracks

- Built a React based web platform that features a piano component that plays sound
- Created a RESTful API with Ruby on Rails that converts MIDI files into JSON format and seeded database with music data

SKILLS



























EXPERIENCE

Director of Operations | Uniworld Tours, Long Island City, NY

April 2010 - December 2016

- Coordinated, facilitated and managed over 100 travel, meeting and special events for businesses and tour groups per year
- Negotiated and reviewed contracts for companies such as Google and IBM, including budget and logistics issues to do with facilities, transportation, lodging, food and entertainment activities

Co-Founder | Flaming Cabbage, Wayne, NJ

February 2008 - June 2009

- Built a website from the ground up including establishing web hosting, SSL, merchant services, Google analytics
- Coordinated over 5 web-hosters and designers to enhance website layout
- Collated site analytic data and implemented SEO strategy to drive growth, increasing site traffic by over 50% in the first year

Internal Auditor | Best Buy, New York, NY

February 2008 - June 2009

- Identified various sources of risks and liabilities such as theft, fraud and damage
- Trained over 30 employees in areas of inventory control, customer service, visual merchandising displays and product knowledge

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY, 2017 Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Immersive Program

City College of New York

New York, NY, 2007 Bachelor of Arts: Sound Engineer